<resources>
    <string name="app_name"> STORY TIME </string>

    <string name="actionSettings">Settings</string>
    <string name="actionReader"> Enable Reader </string>
    <string name="actionFontSize"> Large Font Size </string>
    <string name="actionNightMode"> Enable Night Mode </string>
    <string name="about"> About </string>

    <string name="title1">"THE MONKEY AND THE CROCODILE"</string>

    <string name="story1">
        "Once upon a time, a clever monkey lived in a tree that bore juicy, red rose apples. He was"
        "very happy. One fine day, a crocodile swam up to that tree and told the monkey that he had"
        "traveled a long distance and was in search of food as he was very hungry. The kind monkey "
        "offered him a few rose apples. The crocodile enjoyed them very much and asked the monkey "
        "whether he could come again for some more fruit. The generous monkey happily agreed.\n"
        "The crocodile returned the next day. And the next. And the next one after that. Soon the "
        "two became very good friends. They discussed their lives, their friends and family, like "
        "all friends do. The crocodile told the monkey that he had a wife and that they lived on "
        "the other side of the river. So the kind monkey offered him some extra rose apples to take"
        "home to his wife. The crocodile’s wife loved the rose apples and made her husband promise "
        "to get her some every day.\n"
        "Meanwhile, the friendship between the monkey and the crocodile deepened as they spent more"
        "and more time together. The crocodile’s wife started getting jealous. She wanted to put an"
        "end to this friendship. So she pretended that she could not believe that her husband could"
        "be friends with a monkey. Her husband tried to convince her that he and the monkey shared "
        "a true friendship. The crocodile’s wife thought to herself that if the monkey lived on a "
        "diet of rose monkeys, his flesh would be very sweet. So she asked the crocodile to invite"
        "the monkey to their house.\n"
        "The crocodile was not happy about this. He tried to make the excuse that it would be "
        "difficult to get the monkey cross the river. But his wife was determined to eat the "
        "monkey’s flesh. So she thought of a plan. One day, she pretended to be very ill and told "
        "the crocodile that the doctor said that she would only recover if she ate a monkey’s heart."
        "If her husband wanted to save her life, he must bring her his friend’s heart.\n"
        "The crocodile was aghast. He was in a dilemma. On the one hand, he loved his friend. "
        On the other, he could not possibly let his" wife die. The crocodile’s wife threatened him"
        "saying that if he did not get her the monkey’s heart, she would surely die.\n"
        "So the crocodile went to the rose apple tree and invited the monkey to come home to meet "
        "his wife. He told the monkey that he could ride across the river on the crocodile’s back. "
        "The monkey happily agreed. As they reached the middle of the river, the crocodile began to"
        "sink. The frightened monkey asked him why he was doing that. The crocodile explained that "
        "he would have to kill the monkey to save his wife’s life. The clever monkey told him that "
        "he would gladly give up his heart to save the life of the crocodile’s wife, but he had left"
        "his heart behind in the rose apple tree. He asked the crocodile to make haste and turn "
        "back so that the monkey could go get his heart from the apple tree.\n"
        "The silly crocodile quickly swam back to the rose apple tree.\n"
        "The monkey scampered up the tree to safety. He told the crocodile to tell his wicked wife"
        "that she had married the biggest fool in the world.\n\n"
   </string>
    <string name="story11">
        "Long, long ago, there lived a huge crocodile in the river Ganges. "
        "The river flowed through a dense jungle. On both sides of the river there stood tall "
        "jamun and other fruit trees. In one such tree there lived a big monkey by the name of "
        "Raktamukha. He ate fruits from the tree and passed his days happily jumping from one "
        "tree to another. Sometimes, he climbed down the tree; took a bath in the river and rested"
        "for a while on its bank. \n"

        "One day, the crocodile came out of the river and sat under the big jamun tree in which "
        "the monkey lived. The monkey who was sitting high on a branch saw the crocodile taking "
        "rest under the tree. He became very eager to talk to the crocodile and cultivate a "
        "friendship with him.\n"

         "Since you're taking rest under the tree, said the moneky, you're my guest. It's my "
        "duty to offer you food.\n"

         "The monkey gave jamuns and other fruits to the crocodile to eat. The crocodile ate them"
        "and thanked the monkey for his hospitality. \n"

        "The monkey and the crocodile talked together for hours and soon they became friends. "
        "They developed such friendship that neither of the two was happy to miss each other's "
        "company even for a single day. Early since morning, the monkey would start looking for"
        "the crocodile, and the crocodile would also swim up to the jamun tree as early as possible."
        "They would sit together, have a hearty chat and the monkey would offer him the delicious"
        "jamuns. This became their daily routine.\n"

        "One day, the monkey gave some fruits to the crocodile for his wife, as well. The crocodile"
        "took the fruits happily to his wife and also narrated the whole story to her.\n"

        "The next day, the crocodile's wife said to her husband, Dear, if these fruits are so "
        "tasty, then the monkey who eats these fruits must be ten times more tasty. Why don't you "
        "bring the heart of this monkey for my meals?\n"

        "The crocodile was shocked to hear these words from his wife. He said, Darling, the monkey"
        "is my friend. It would not be fair to take his heart away from him.\n"

        "That means, you don't love me, said the crocodile's wife and began to weep."

        "Don't weep, dear, said the crocodile. I'll bring the monkey's heart for you."

        "The crocodile swiftly swam to the other bank of the river and reached the tree where"
        "the monkey lived.\n"

        "My wife and I invite you to our home for a dinner. My wife is very angry with me for not"
        "having invited you earlier, the crocodile said in a sad tone.\n"

         "But how will I go with you? asked the monkey. I don't know how to swim.\n"

         "Don't worry, said the crocodile. Just ride on my back. I'll take you to my house.\n"

         "The monkey happily sat on the back of the crocodile and the crocodile started his journey"
         "in the water.\n"

         "While in mid stream, the monkey became frightened to see the water all around him and "
         "asked the crocodile to swim at a slow speed so that he did not fall into the river.\n"

         "The crocodile thought that he could reveal his real intentions to the monkey, since it"
         "was impossible for him to escape from the middle of the river. So he said to the monkey,"
         "I am taking you to my home to please my wife. She wants to eat your heart. She says that"
         "since you eat tasty fruits day and night, your heart must be ten times more tasty than "
         "those fruits.\n"

         "The monkey was taken aback to hear these words. He had never expected this type of a "
         "request from a friend. He kept his mental cool and said wittingly, Very well friend. "
         "It would be my privilege to offer my heart to your charming wife. But alas! you didn't "
         "inform me earlier, otherwise, I'd have carried my heart with me. Which I usually keep "
         "in the hollow of the tree.\n"

         "Oh! said the crocodile, I didn't think of it earlier. Now we'll have to go back to the"
         "tree.\n"
         "The crocodile turned and swam back to the bank of the river where the monkey lived.\n"
         "Upon reaching the bank the monkey jumped off the crocodile's back and quickly climbed up "
         "his home tree. \n"

         "The crocodile waited for hours together for the monkey to return carrying his heart.\n"

         "When the crocodile realised that the monkey was taking too long searching for his heart,"
         "he called him from the ground and said, Friend, I believe, you must have found your heart"
         "by now. Now, please come down. My wife must be waiting for us and getting worried.\n"

         "But the monkey laughed and said sitting at the top of the tree, My dear foolish friend."
         "You've deceived me as a friend. Can any one take out his heart and keep that in a hollow."
         "It was all a trick to save my life and teach a lesson to a treacherous friend like you. "
         "Now get lost.\n"
         "The crocodile returned home with his head bent down. \n"

    </string>

    <string name="title2"> THE SHEPHERD AND THE WOLF </string>
    <string name="story2">
    "There lived a shepherd in a village. He had many sheep. He took them out every morning for "
    "grazing. One day, his wife fell ill and he had to go to the city to purchase some medicines "
    "for his ailing wife. 'There will be no one to take care of the sheep', he thought to himself."
    "Then he called his son and told him, Ramu, I'm going to the city to purchase some medicines "
    "for your mother. It will take me two or three days to come back. So take care of the sheep."
    "Save them from being attacked by the tigers and wolves. There are many wild animals in the "
    "nearby forest. They might kill our sheep.\n"

    "Ramu listened to his father's advice carefully and the next day, he left for the nearby "
    "hillside with his flock of sheep. But Ramu was a mischievous boy. He was feeling lonely. "
    "So he wanted to have some fun. He stood on a high rock and began shouting Wolf! wolf!, help. \n"

    "The villagers heard Ramu crying for help. They ran towards the hillside to help the boy, "
    "carrying big sticks in their hands. When they reached there they found that there was no "
    "wolf. The sheep were grazing happily and the shepherd boy was playing on a flute. \n"

    "Where is the wolf? the villagers asked the boy.\n"

    "There is no wolf here. I was joking, the boy said and laughed.\n"

    "The villagers became very angry and returned to their work in the village. \n"

    "Next day, the boy played the same trick. The villagers again reached there to help the boy."
    "But when they came to know that the boy was lying, they felt highly annoyed and went back to "
    "the village cursing the boy. \n"

    "But on the third day, a wolf really came there. The boy got frightened to see his red eyes. "
    "The wolf was huffing and growling. He began advancing towards the flock of sheep, gnashing "
    "his teeth and lolling his tongue. The boy lost his courage and began trembling with fear. "
    "He shouted, Wolf, wolf, please help! But to no avail.\n"

    "This time no one came to help him. The villagers thought that Ramu was up to his old trick.\n"
    "The wolf killed many sheep of Ramu. Ramu returned home weeping.\n\n"

</string>
    <string name="title3"> THE FOUR FRIENDS AND THE HUNTER </string>
    <string name="story3">
    "Long, long ago, there lived three friends in a jungle. They were-a deer, a crow and a mouse. "
        "They used to share their meals together. \n"
        "One day, a turtle came to them and said, I also want to join your company and become your"
        "friend. I'm all alone. \n"

        "You're most welcome, said the crow. But what about your personal safety. There are many"
        "hunters around. They visit this jungle regularly. Suppose, a hunter comes, how will you"
        "save yourself? \n"

        "That is the reason why I want to join your group, said the turtle \n"

        "No sooner had they talked about it than a hunter appeared on the scene. Seeing the hunter,"
        "the deer darted away; the crow flew in the sky and the mouse ran into a hole. The turtle"
        "tried to crawl away fast, but he was caught by the hunter. The hunter tied him up in the "
        "net. He was sad to lose the deer. But he thought, it was better to feast on the turtle "
        "rather than to go hungry. \n"

        "The turtle's three friends became much worried to see his friend trapped by the hunter."
        "They sat together to think of some plan to free his friend from the hunter's snare.\n"

        "The crow then flew high up in the sky and spotted the hunter walking along the river bank."
        "As per the plan the deer ran ahead of the hunter unnoticed and lay on the hunter's path as"
        "if dead.\n"

        "The hunter saw the deer from a distance, lying on the ground. He was very happy to have "
        "found it again. Now I'll have a good feast on it and sell its beautiful skin in the market,"
        "thought the hunter to himself. He put down the turtle on to the ground and ran to pick up "
        "the deer. \n"

        "In the meantime, as planned, the rat gnawed through the net and freed the turtle. The "
        "turtle hurriedly crawled away into the river water. \n"

        "Unaware of the plot of these friends, the hunter went to fetch the dear for its tasty "
        "flesh and beautiful skin. But, what he saw with his mouth agape was that, when he reached"
        "near, the deer suddenly sprang up to its feet and darted away in the jungle. Before he "
        "could understand anything, the deer had disappeared. \n"

        "Dejected, the hunter turned back to collect the turtle he had left behind on the ground"
        "in the snare. But he was shocked to see the snare lying nibbled at and the turtle missing."
        "For a moment, the hunter thought that he was dreaming. But the damaged snare lying on the "
        "ground was proof enough to confirm that he was very much awake and he was compelled to "
        "believe that some miracle had taken place. \n"

        "The hunter got frightened on account of these happenings and ran out of the jungle. \n"

        "The four friends once again started living happily \n\n"
  </string>
    <string name="title4"> THE TALKATIVE TORTOISE </string>
    <string name="story4">
        "Once upon a time, two geese by the names of Sankata and Vikata and a tortoise by the name"
        "of Kambugriva lived near a river. They were good friends. Once, due to drought in the "
        "region, all the rivers, lakes and ponds went dry. There was not a drop of water to drink "
        "for the birds and animals. They began to die of thirst.\n"

        "The three friends talked among themselves to find a solution to this problem and go out"
        "in search of water. But despite their best efforts they could not find water anywhere "
        "around. \n"

        "Having no alternative the three friends decided to go to some distant lake, full of water,"
        "to settle down there forever. But there was a problem in shifting to so distant a place. "
        "While it was easy for the geese to fly, it was difficult for the tortoise to cover that "
        "distance on foot.\n"

        "So the tortoise put up a bright idea. He said, Why not bring a strong stick? I will hold"
        "the stick in the middle with my teeth and you two hold both the ends of the stick in your"
        "beaks. In this manner, I can also travel with you. \n"

        "Hearing the suggestion of the tortoise, the geese cautioned him, It's a very good idea. "
        "We will do as you say. But you will have to be very careful. The problem with you is that"
        "you are very talkative. And if you open your mouth to say something, while we are flying,"
        "it will definitely prove to be detrimental to you. So, don't talk while you are dangling "
        "by the stick, otherwise you will lose your hold and go crashing down on the ground and die.\n"

        "The tortoise understood the logic and promised not to open his mouth during the entire "
        "journey. So the geese held the stick ends in their beaks and the tortoise held the stick"
        "in the middle with his teeth and thus, they began their long journey.\n"

        "They flew over hills, valleys, villages, forests and finally came over a town. While they"
        "were flying over the town, men, women and children came out of their houses to see this"
        "strange sight. The children began shouting and clapping. The foolish tortoise forgot that"
        "he was hanging precariously. He became so curious to know the reason behind these clapping"
        "that he opened his mouth to ask his friends-Friends, what is this all about? But as soon "
        "as he opened his, mouth to utter these words, he loosened his hold on the stick and fell "
        "down on the ground and died instantaneously.\n\n"
   </string>
    <string name="title5">WHO WILL BELL THE CAT?</string>
    <string name="story5">
        "Once upon a time, there lived many mice in a grocer’s shop. There in the shop, they ate"
        "delicious wheat and rice, pulses and nuts, bread and butter and biscuits. They grew fat"
        "day by day.\n"

        "One day, the grocer thought about the heavy losses that he had to suffer because of the"
        "menace of the mice. This angered him so much, that the next day, he brought a big fat "
        "cat to his shop.\n"

        "The big fat cat began to catch and kill the fat mice everyday.\n"

        "The mice became worried. They called a meeting to discuss the problem.\n"

        "Let's get rid of this cruel fat cat, the leader of the mice said. \n"

        "But how? the other mice asked.\n"

        "All of them began to think. Then one mouse said, We should tie a bell round the neck of "
        "the fat cat. So, whenever she would move towards us, the bell would ring and we will run"
        "into our holes immediately.\n"

        "All the mice became very happy to hear this. They began dancing with joy. But their joy "
        "was short-lived. An old and experienced mouse interrupted their merry-making and shouted,"
        "Fools, stop it and tell me, who’ll bell the cat?\n"

        "No mouse had the answer to this big question.\n\n"

   </string>
    <string name="title6">THE JACKAL AND THE ARROW</string>
    <string name="story6">
        "Once a hunter was hunting in a forest. After sometime, he felt hungry. He saw a wild boar"
        "coming towards him. He shot an arrow at the boar. The arrow pierced the boar's neck and"
        "protruded at its back.\n"

        "But the boar, before falling on the ground, killed the hunter with his pointed tusks. "
        "Soon the hunter and the boar both were lying dead at the same spot.\n"

        "At the same time, a hungry jackal happened to pass through that place. He saw a man and"
        "an animal, both lying dead there. 'What a good luck I have? So much food to eat for days"
        "together', thought the jackal to himself. He began to think whose flesh to eat first – the"
        "man or the animal.\n"

        "He decided to go slow at the eating, so that the food would last for a longer period.\n"

        "The jackal decided first to lick the blood and eat a little flesh stuck round the tusks"
        "of the boar. But, as soon as, he put the pointed tip of the boar’s tusks in his mouth it"
        "pierced his jaws and went through his head. The jackal died on the spot.\n"

        "Greed never pays!!!! \n\n"
   </string>
    <string name="title7">THE WIND AND THE SUN</string>
    <string name="story7">
        "Once an argument took place between the wind and the sun as to who was stronger of the two."
        "The wind claimed that he was stronger than the sun, whereas, the sun disagreed saying that"
        "he was more powerful than the wind.\n"

        "Of course, this was a friendly argument, but there seemed to be no end to if. After a"
        "marathon discussion, they both came to the conclusion that mere discussion won't serve"
        "any purpose. They, practically, have to do something to prove their point.\n"

        "Just then, they saw a traveller walking down the road. The sun got a bright idea and "
        "said to the wind, Let's test our strength on that man. Whosoever of us can force him "
        "take off his jacket, shall be considered the winner. Have your chance first.\n"

        "Saying this the sun hid himself behind clouds and got ready to see the fun.\n"

        "The wind took the first turn. He blew an icy blast. But the harder he blew, \n"
        "the more closely did the traveller wrap his jacket around his body. The wind "
        "tried everything; clung to every ruse. He heaved his stormy power from all "
        "sides, but all in vain. His confidence in his mightiness began shattering "
        "gradually. And ultimately, out of sheer disgust and embarrassment the wind gave up.\n"

        "Now it was the sun's turn. He gently put aside the patch of cloud which served as a veil"
        "a moment ago. The anthelion around the cloud disappeared and now the sun was in the open "
        "field with all his vigour. He began to shine with all his might. The traveller felt the "
        "warmth of the sun. Then gradually the sun grew hotter and hotter. The traveller first "
        "loosened his jacket and then finally, took it off. He began to perspire. He sat in the "
        "shade of a tree and fanned himself.\n"

        "Thus, the sun proved himself to be stronger than the wind. \n\n"
        "Persuasion can achieve, what a brute force can't. \n\n"

</string>
    <string name="title8">THE LION AND THE HARE</string>
    <string name="story8">
        "There lived a lion by the name of Bhasuraka, in a dense jungle. He was very powerful, "
        "cruel and arrogant. He used to kill the animals of the jungle unnecessarily. He even "
        "killed the human beings, who travelled through the jungle. This became a cause of worry"
        "for all the animals. They discussed this problem among themselves and ultimately came upon"
        "a decision to hold a meeting with the lion and make an amicable settlement with him and "
        "put an end to this ongoing trauma. \n"

        "So, one day, all the animals of the jungle assembled under a big tree. They also invited "
        "king lion to attend the- meeting. In the meeting the animals said to king lion, "
        "Your Majesty, we are happy that you are our king. We are all-the-more happy that"
        "you are presiding over the meeting. King lion thanked them and asked, Why is it that we"
        "have gathered here? All the animals began looking at each other. They had to muster "
        "enough courage to broach the topic. Sir, said one of the animals, Its natural that you "
        "kill us for food. But, killing more than what is required is a positive vice and "
        "unnecessary. If you go on killing the animals without any purpose, soon a day will come, "
        "when there will be no animals left in the jungle.\n"

        "So what do you want? roared king lion.\n"

        "Your Majesty, we have already discussed the problem among ourselves and have come upon"
        "a solution. We have decided to send one animal a day to your den. You can kill and eat it."
        "This will save you from the trouble of hunting and you will not have to kill a number of "
        "animals unnecessarily for your meals.\n"

        "Good, the lion roared back. I agree to this proposal, but the animals must reach to me in"
        "time, otherwise, I'll kill all the animals of the jungle.\n"

        "The animals agreed to this proposal. Everyday one animal walked into the lion's den to"
        "become his feast. The lion too was very happy to have his food right before him. He "
        "stopped hunting for his prey.\n"

        "One day, it was the turn of a hare to go into the lion's den. The little hare was "
        "unwilling to go and become a meal of the lion, but the other animals forced him to go to "
        "the lion's den. \n"

        "Having no alternative, the hare began thinking quickly. He thought of a plan. He began "
        "wandering around and made a deliberate delay, and reached the lion's den a little late "
        "than the lion's meal time. By now, the lion had already lost his patience and seeing the"
        "hare coming slowly, he became furious and demanded for an explanation.\n"

        "Your Majesty, the hare said with folded hands, I am not to be blamed for that. I have "
        "come late because another lion began chasing me and wanted to eat me. He said that he "
        "too was the king of the jiungle.\n"

        "The king lion roared in great anger and said, Impossible, there cannot exist another "
        "king in this jungle. Who is he? I'll kill him. Show me where he lives.\n"

        "The lion and the hare set out to face the other lion. The hare took the lion to a deep "
        "well, full of water.\n"

        "When they reached near the well, the hare said to the lion, This is the place where he"
        "lives. He might be hiding inside.\n"

        "The lion again roared in great anger; climbed up the puteal of the well and peeped in."
        "He saw his own reflection in the water and thought that the other lion was challenging"
        "his authority. He lost his temper.\n"

    "I must kill him, said the lion unto himself and jumped into the well. He was soon drowned.\n"

        "The hare was happy. He went back to other animals and narrated the whole story. All the "
        "animals took a sigh of relief and praised him for his cleverness. They all lived happily"
        "thereafter. \n

       " Intelligence is superior to physical strength. \n\n"

</string>
</resources>
